Radika Permana

Address: Jl. Pondok Pinang 2 No.20 Jakarta Selatan, 12310

Phone: 0856-59336390 Fax: E-Mail: radikapermana@gmail.com



Summary of Qualifications

A well-versed professional with 4 years of experience in automotive industry. Key qualification include hands-on skills in short, mid and long-term sales planning management, fleet management, customer relationship management, fix and variable marketing management and market analysis.

Experience

PT. Ford Motor Indonesia

Jun 2014 - Present

[Sales Planning Analyst]

- Review overall industry growth in Indonesia registered under Gaikindo for both wholesale and retailsales based on vehicle segments and brands.
- Manage vehicle availability and distribution for all dealers to achieve sales program by stock availability, shipment schedule, wholesale availability, retail availability, and vehicle clearance.
- Supporting Dealer Operation Manager and Sales Planning Manager with monthly allocation by analyze average sales monthly in a particular region and feeding relevant data and information to develop Sales Stock Run-Down (SSRD).
- Ordering vehicle from regional factory in order to distribute and allocate to dealer based on sales program.

PT. Ford Motor Indonesia

Apr 2012 - Jun 2014

[Fleet Sales & CRM Analyst]

- Analyzing fleet sales and forecast to develop fleet sales program.
- Manage variable marketing budget to support dealer through fleet incentive base on project requirement,
 fleet sales history and fleet units in operation
- Create fleet activity and manage fixed marketing budget to support fleet marketing activity and brand awareness through fleet exhibition, fleet gathering and 4x4 safety driving.
- Manage fleet database in order to develop retain customer program.

PT. Ford Motor Indonesia

Mar 2010 - Apr 2012

[Retail & Wholesale Analyst]

- Monitoring wholesale and retail report to analyze market trend.
- Creating faktur request to all dealers.
- Creating Conditional Sales Invoice (CSI) request and preparing tax invoice to all dealers.
- Reviewing monthly interest and storage cost.

Education

Widyatama University, Bandung

2003-2009

[Information Technology]

Major in Information Technology with particular interest in multimedia (Web Design, Animation, Software Application).

Skills

Language : Indonesia, English

Computer Skills: MS Office (MS Word, MS Excell, MS Power Point, MS Outlook), SAP CRM, GOaLS

Flash, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Internet.

Training and Course

Fleet Management Training – Jakarta, Sep 2012

- Sales Planning Management Intermediate Training Bangkok, Sep 2011
- Personal Sales Planning and Prospecting Training Jakarta, Mar 2011
- Drum Course at Purwacaraka Music School 2008
- English Course at EEP Bandung, 2007

Achievement

 Project leader of Global Ordering and Logistic System (GOaLS) application and conduct training GOaLS retail reporting application to all dealers - Jun 2010

Personal Particulars

Place, Date of Birth : Jakarta, Jan 17th 1985

Height/Weight : 165 / 50 Gender : Male

License : "A" and "C" Driving Licenses holder

Interest : Design, Music, and Sport